[
  {
    "id": "a0001",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is a non communicable disease?",
    "correctAnswer": "Diabetes",
    "optionValues": [
      "Chicken Pox",
      "Measles",
      "Diabetes",
      "Tuberculosis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0002",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following behavior modification ideas would you keep in mind when you go for grocery shopping?",
    "correctAnswer": "Shop from a list and avoid buying anything that is not on your list",
    "optionValues": [
      "Shop when you are feeling hungry",
      "Taste test everything available in the store",
      "Purchase food without reading food labels",
      "Shop from a list and avoid buying anything that is not on your list"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0003",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Calcium and ________ are essential for healthy bones",
    "correctAnswer": "Vitamin D",
    "optionValues": [
      "Vitamin K",
      "Vitamin C",
      "Vitamin E",
      "Vitamin D"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0004",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What is the full form of CDC?",
    "correctAnswer": "Centers for Disease Control and Prevention",
    "optionValues": [
      "Cabinet for Disease Control and Prevention",
      "Centers for Disease Control and Prevention",
      "Commission for Disease Control and Prevention",
      "Congregation for Disease Control and Prevention"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0005",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "___________ is the condition of not having enough sleep",
    "correctAnswer": "Sleep deprivation",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sleep deprivation",
      "Sleepover",
      "Sleepwalking",
      "Sleep paralysis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0006",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which is the common test used to measure Speed as a component of fitness in an individual?",
    "correctAnswer": "40-yard dash",
    "optionValues": [
      "20-yard dash",
      "100-yard dash",
      "40-yard dash",
      "50-yard dash"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0007",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Adult blood pressure is considered normal at",
    "correctAnswer": "120/80 mm Hg",
    "optionValues": [
      "100/80 mm Hg",
      "120/100 mm Hg",
      "120/80 mm Hg",
      "100/70 mm Hg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0008",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "On an average women has ____ % of body fat",
    "correctAnswer": "25 to 31 %",
    "optionValues": [
      "25 to 31 %",
      "40 to 45 %",
      "40 to 50 %",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0009",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The most common cause of COPD is",
    "correctAnswer": "Smoking",
    "optionValues": [
      "High blood pressure",
      "Raised glucose levels in the blood",
      "Alcohol",
      "Smoking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0010",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following methods is considered as the new 'Gold Standard' in body composition testing?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry",
    "optionValues": [
      "Air displacement plethysmography",
      "Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry",
      "Underwater weighing",
      "Bioelectric Impedance Analysis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0011",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following metabolic risk factors contribute to the risk of NCDs?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Raised blood pressure",
      "Overweight/obesity",
	  "High blood glucose levels",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0012",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "_________ is defined as the body mass in kilograms divided by the square of the body height in metres",
    "correctAnswer": "Body mass index",
    "optionValues": [
      "Ideal body weight",
      "Bone mineral content",
	  "Body mass index",
	  "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0013",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following are signs and symptoms of hypercholesterolemia?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Xanthomata",
      "Xanthelasma",
	  "Corneal arcus",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0014",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following are the components of fitness?",
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "optionValues": [
      "Cardiorespiratory endurance",
      "Muscular endurance",
	  "Muscular strength",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0015",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Abdominal obesity, triglyceride level of 200mg/dL and fasting glucose of 150mg/dL indicates the person is suffering from __________",
    "correctAnswer": "Metabolic syndrome",
    "optionValues": [
      "Cancer",
      "Asthma",
	  "Metabolic syndrome",
	  "Arthritis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0016",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which component of fitness is measured using the Cooper run?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cardiorespiratory endurance",
    "optionValues": [
      "Speed",
      "Cardiorespiratory endurance",
	  "Muscular strength",
	  "Balance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0017",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Chest tightness, breathlessness and wheezing are symptoms of ________________",
    "correctAnswer": "Asthma",
    "optionValues": [
      "Osteoporosis",
      "Diabetes",
	  "Asthma",
	  "Hypertension"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0018",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following are the benefits of fitness?",
    "correctAnswer": "Both (First and second options)",
    "optionValues": [
      "Regular physical activity can improve your muscle strength and boost your endurance",
      "Improves heart health",
	  "Both (First and second options)",
	  "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0019",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which statement is correct for Osteoporosis:-",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Osteoporosis means Decrease in density of bones",
      "The risk of osteoporosis increases after menopause",
	  "There is loss of bone mass",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0020",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Body composition is used to describe the percentages of ___________",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Body Fat",
      "Bone",
	  "Muscle and water",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0021",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "___________ is defined as the ability to carry out daily tasks with vigor and alertness, without undue fatigue, and with ample energy to enjoy leisure-time pursuits and respond to emergencies.",
    "correctAnswer": "Physical fitness",
    "optionValues": [
      "Mental fitness",
      "Physical fitness",
	  "Cardiovascular fitness",
	  "Muscular fitness"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0022",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Broca’s Formula for IBW estimation for male",
    "correctAnswer": "Ht. (cms) – 100",
    "optionValues": [
      "Ht. (cms) – 100",
      "Ht. (inch) – 100",
	  "Ht. (cms) – 105",
	  "Ht. (inch) – 105"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0023",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following food is permitted to be consumed  in plenty  by a person suffering from Diabetes?",
    "correctAnswer": "Green leafy vegetables",
    "optionValues": [
      "Mango",
      "Green leafy vegetables",
	  "Sweetened juices",
	  "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0024",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "BMI cutoff for normal individual according to WHO is ______",
    "correctAnswer": "18.5 to 25 kg/m2",
    "optionValues": [
      "18.5 to 25 kg/m2",
      "17.5 to 30 kg/m2",
	  "25 to 30 kg/m2",
	  "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0025",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is a side effect of cancer therapy?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Nausea and vomiting",
      "Loss of appetite",
	  "Sore mouth and throat",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0026",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which is the most important but often overlooked component of fitness?",
    "correctAnswer": "Flexibility",
    "optionValues": [
      "Balance",
      "Speed",
	  "Flexibility",
	  "Body composition"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0027",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Female Hormone that is essential for healthy bones",
    "correctAnswer": "Estrogen",
    "optionValues": [
      "Progesterone",
      "Estrogen",
	  "Progesterone and estrogen",
	  "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0028",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "In low sodium diet, which of the following food items can be used to make the food more palatable and appetizing?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Spices",
      "Herbs",
	  "Lemon juice",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0029",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following food items would make an excellent snack choice for a child coming back from school?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fruit yoghurt",
    "optionValues": [
      "Fruit yoghurt",
      "Chocolate",
	  "Potato wafers",
	  "Pizza"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0030",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following is not recommended to Hypertensive Patient?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "pickles",
      "canned foods",
	  "potato chips",
	  "All of the above"
    ]
  }
]